cmcmarkets.com.au 2013-10-05

# Privacy statement | CMC Markets

* * *

## This privacy statement explains how the CMC Markets Group (‘CMC Markets’) collects, maintains, uses and discloses your personal information.

It also provides some detail about the rights that customers have in respect of their personal information. For the purpose of this Privacy Statement, members of the CMC Markets Group include CMC Markets Asia Pacific Pty Ltd (ABN 11 100 058 213), CMC Markets Stockbroking Limited (ABN 69 081 002 851), CMC Markets Pty Ltd (ABN 75 100 058 106) and other related companies. 

**Personal information**  
You provide CMC Markets with your personal information when you ask for information about CMC Markets’ products and services, when you access and use this and other CMC Markets websites, and/or when you submit an application to open an account with CMC Markets. When assessing an application, CMC Markets may also collect information about you from publicly available sources such as company registers. 

If you give us personal information about another person, you represent that you are authorised to do so and agree to inform that person who we are, that we will use and disclose that information for the relevant purposes set out below, and that they can access the information we hold about them. 

CMC Markets maintains records of all transactions and activities on accounts you have with CMC Markets, including details of contracts traded and margin calls made. During the course of your relationship with CMC Markets, we will also gather information about products and services provided to you. 

We are required by law to collect information to identify and verify you. CMC Markets may make enquiries as to your identity(ies) and other personal details as required by the Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorism Financing Act 2006. Your personal information will be treated strictly in accordance with the National Privacy Principles in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and the ‘private sector amendments’ contained in the Privacy Amendment (Private Sector) Act 2000 (Cth). 

We may also use your personal information to obtain a credit report from a credit reporting agency containing personal credit information about you and/or contacting any credit provider named in the credit report or any credit provider whose details have been provided to us by you in order to obtain information relevant to opening your account or collecting overdue payments in relation to any trading activity. 

**Telephone conversations**  
CMC Markets may record telephone conversations between you and persons working for CMC Markets. Such recordings, or transcripts from such recordings, may be used to resolve any dispute between you and CMC Markets. 

**CMC Markets’ websites – statistical information and cookies**  
We collect statistical information about visitors to our websites such as the number of visitors, pages viewed, types of transactions conducted, time online and documents downloaded. This information is used to evaluate and improve the performance of our websites. Other than statistical information, we do not collect any information about you through our website unless you provide the information to us. 

You should also be aware that we use cookies on our websites. A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes a unique identification number or value that is sent to your browser from a website’s computer and stored on your computer’s hard drive. Each website can send its own cookies to your browser if your browser allows it. However, to protect your privacy, your browser only allows a website to access the cookies it has sent to your computer. 

When cookies are used on our websites, they are used to collect the statistical information referred to above in addition to allowing you to access your account online. When you access your account online, a cookie will be created which uniquely identifies your computer and your username and password. This means that you do not have to re-enter those details each time you want to access your account online. 

Most internet browsers are set up to accept cookies. If you do not wish to receive cookies, you may be able to change the settings of your browser to refuse all cookies or to have your computer notify you each time a cookie is sent to it, and thereby give yourself the choice whether to accept it or not. If you reject all cookies, you will be unable to access your account online. You can also delete cookies from your computer after they have been created. 

**Use of the information by CMC Markets**  
The information requested in any application to open an account completed by customers is required to enable us to provide a service to you. That information, together with the information collected and maintained by CMC Markets during the course of our relationship with you, is used to manage and administer the products and services provided to you and to keep you updated whilst you are a customer in relation to various matters including the contracts you have traded, your margin obligations, the funds in your account, and other activities of CMC Markets. 

We may also use your personal information to develop an understanding of the products and services that you may be interested in obtaining from CMC Markets and to market such products and services to you. 

**CMC Markets may disclose your personal information to:**

  * financial institutions and other similar organisations that it deals with in the course of its corporate activities, or those that are nominated by you; 
  * external service providers and professional advisers (which may be located overseas) that provide services to us; 
  * any organisation at your request or any persons acting on your behalf, including your financial adviser, broker, solicitor or accountant;
  * credit reporting agency, any credit provider named in the report and any credit provider whose details have been provided to us by you; 
  * regulatory and government bodies from time to time in Australia and other countries; and 
  * CMC Markets plc and its associates. 

CMC Markets takes all reasonable steps to protect your personal information from misuse, loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. 

**What are your rights?**  
You need not give us any of the personal information requested by CMC Markets. However, without that information CMC Markets will not be able to open an account for you where the information is requested in an application form, or to provide you with any other services, information or assistance you have sought. 

Should you have any questions or complaint about your privacy please contact us. If a complaint is not resolved by CMC Markets to your satisfaction, you may complain to the Privacy Commissioner. 

**Access to information by customers**  
Customers can gain access to any information CMC Markets holds about them by calling **1300 660 262** or emailing **clientservices@cmcmarkets.com.au.** We will process your request usually within 14 days. If your request is complex, more time may be needed in which case we will advise you of the extra time required. 

There is no fee for requesting access to your information, although CMC Markets may charge you the reasonable cost of processing your request. 

In some circumstances the law may allow CMC Markets to deny you access. In such a case we will explain to you the reason for refusing access. 

**Correction of information**  
We ask that you promptly notify us of any changes to the personal information that CMC Markets holds about you. This ensures that your personal information is up to date and enables us to keep you informed of the continuing circumstances of your account, your margin obligations and your trading activities. 

You may ask us at any time to correct personal information held by CMC Markets about you, and which you believe is inaccurate. If we disagree with you as to the accuracy of the information, you may request that we attach a statement to that information noting that you consider it inaccurate or incomplete. 

**‘Do not call’ register**  
Unless you ask us by calling **1300 660 262** not to contact you about products or services and not to disclose your information to others for that purpose, by accessing this website you consent to us contacting you by telephone while you hold any product or receive any services from us notwithstanding registration at any time of your telephone number on the ‘do not call’ register. 

**Receiving commercial electronic messages**  
By accessing this website you consent to us sending commercial electronic messages (including messages about our products and services) to any electronic address which you provide or for which you are responsible. You warrant that you have authority, either as or on behalf of the electronic account holder, to provide this consent and agree that until you withdraw your consent by providing written notice to us or using an unsubscribe facility in the message, we may continue to send commercial electronic messages to those addresses. 

**Your consent**  
By accessing this website or by submitting an application to open an account with CMC Markets, you consent to CMC Markets collecting, maintaining, using and disclosing personal information about you and provided by you or by another person as described above. 

**Amendments to this privacy statement**  
CMC Markets may make changes to this privacy statement from time to time for any reason. This privacy statement is dated 6 April 2010.
